Milos Vasic, curriculum vitae



About

Software Engineer from Belgrade, Serbia. In software development since 2009. Experience with full software development lifecycle. Planning, development and team leading, deployment.

Speaking languages: Serbian and English. Also Russian with basic understanding without conversation.

The main development technology

- Android, JetPack Compose, MVVP, Kotlin Flow, Kotlin Coroutines, Live Data, Retrofit, OkHttp, Firebase, Dagger, Hilt, etc.
- Kotlin Multiplatform
- React Native, Expo, Npm, Yarn

Familiar with

- Flutter (Dart)
- iOS with Swift (Legacy and Swift UI)

Work experience

Through the career have been working on the various projects and with various clients.

Fulltime positions

- Harness Belgrade, Serbia (full-time), from 03/2020 until 12/2024, Staff Software Engineer (various technologies) [TECHNOLOGY: Android, iOS, Flutter, React Native, TypeScript, JavaScript, Java, Kotlin, Swift, Go, Ruby]
- Leica Geosystems Heerbrugg, Switzerland (full-time), from 02/2016 until 02/2020, Android and iOS
 Developer (with C++ core) [TECHNOLOGY: Android, iOS, Java, Kotlin, Swift, C++]
- Bosch Belgrade, Serbia (full-time), from 01/2010 until 01/2016, Android SDK Developer
 [TECHNOLOGY: Android, Java, Kotlin]

Other projects involved

- TN-TECH Novi Sad, Serbia (part-time), from 03/2017 [TECHNOLOGY: Android, Java, Kotlin, C++,
 QT]
 - Globex Data (Canada and Switzerland): Sekur (SekurMessenger), SekurMail, SekurSuite
 - BusRide platform
- Increment Loop Belgrade, Serbia (part-time), from 09/2023 [TECHNOLOGY: Android, Kotlin]
 - Yuno
- HelixTrack [TECHNOLOGY: C++, Bash, SQL, Postgres, Drogon, etc.]
- Server Factory [TECHNOLOGY: Java, Kotlin, Bash]
 - Mail Server Factory
 - o Parallels Utils
 - Qemu Utils
- Android Toolkit [TECHNOLOGY: Android, Java, Kotlin]

Other technology

Familiar with the following technology as well:

Desktop development

- Electron
- Java (Swing and Fx)
- C++ (QT with Qmake or Cmake with Ninja and Konan)
- Flutter (Desktop)
- React Native (Desktop)
- Kotlin Multiplatform (Desktop)
- macOS with Swift

Backend development

- GoLang (Gin Gonic)
- Java and Kotlin (Spring / Spring Boot with Maven and Gradle)
- Python (Pyramid, Flask with Waitress)
- Ruby (Ruby on Rails)
- C++ (Drogon with Cmake, Ninja and Konan)
- Docker, Docker Compose

Web development

React

- Angular
- JavaScript and TypeScript
- HTML, CSS

Data and Databases

- PostgreSQL
- MySQL
- Sqlite
- Firebase
- MongoDB
- Redis
- Apache Kafka
- RabbitMQ

Various

- Bash
- Git, SVN, Perforce
- GitHub (with Copilot) GitLab, GitFlic, Gitee, Gitverse
- Gradle, MVN, CMake, Ninja, etc.
- JIRA, Confluence, Active Collab
- Jenkins, Travis, Circle Cl, Bitbucket Pipelines, GitHub Actions, All from Harness
- macOS, Linux, Microsoft Windows
- All JetBrains IDEs, GIGA IDE, VSCode, etc.
- XCode
- REST API, WebSockets, SIP, Matrix, SSDP, Quic, etc.
- SonarQube

Author work

Worked on several programming books as self-published author and author for Packt Publishing UK.

Self-published: Fundamental Kotlin, Last edition: Fundamental-Kotlin: revised (September 6, 2022.)

Education

- Bachelor of Science: Informatics and Computing, 2008. University Singidunum, Belgrade (Serbia)
- M.Sc: Contemporary Information Technologies, 2014. University Singidunum, Belgrade (Serbia)

Contacts and links

- E-Mail: i@mvasic.ru
- Mobile: +381 69 25 35 718 (Serbia), +7 966 323 77 17 (Russian Federation)
- Telegram: milos85vasic
- Networks: Linkedin, TenChat, Xing, VK
- Source code and Open-Source: GitHub, GitFlic, Gitee